<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>blog.strongtownscalgary</title>
    <link href="https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca" />
    <updated>2024-05-22T15:29:18-06:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>StrongTownsCalgary</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Rezoning for Housing</title>
        <author>
            <name>StrongTownsCalgary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/rezoning-for-housing.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/rezoning-for-housing.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-22T15:29:18-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    April 2024 The City of Calgary has proposed an end to exclusionary zoning citywide, meaning that properties that would previously only allow for only one, or two units on a lot would have the freedom to develop secondary suites, basement suites, duplexes, row housing, cottage&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>April 2024</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/Pasted-image-20240522124901.png" alt="" width="715" height="406" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124901-xs.png 300w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124901-sm.png 480w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124901-md.png 768w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124901-lg.png 1024w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124901-xl.png 1360w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124901-2xl.png 1600w"></figure>
<p><strong>The City of Calgary</strong> has proposed an end to exclusionary zoning citywide, meaning that properties that would previously only allow for only one, or two units on a lot would have the freedom to develop secondary suites, basement suites, duplexes, row housing, cottage courts, or just remain the same!</p>
<p>At <strong>Strong Towns Calgary</strong>, we support this and any other zoning reform initiative that seeks to enable incremental development. Allowing greater flexibility with our land ensures that communities can adapt to their needs, and the City can more easily finance services and infrastructure</p>
<h2><strong>Take Action Today!</strong></h2>
<p>Our friends at More Neighbours Calgary have released a blog post detailing how to sign up to speak at the Public Hearing on April 22nd. The hearing will likely span several days, and you can always phone-in remotely, or write a letter! It is incredibly important that you voice your support on this issue. Municipal politics is where your voice has the greatest impact in creating the change we want to see. Keep scrolling to learn the facts about R-CG, and why we believe it's so important.</p>
<h2><strong>Rezoning for affordability!</strong></h2>
<p>It's not a silver bullet, but we can't afford to ignore it.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/Pasted-image-20240522124945.png" alt="" width="894" height="548" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124945-xs.png 300w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124945-sm.png 480w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124945-md.png 768w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124945-lg.png 1024w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124945-xl.png 1360w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522124945-2xl.png 1600w"></figure>
<p>Four is the magic number of units for newly-built infill housing to sell at the same price as what it replaced. Anything less drastically inflates the cost of housing, or renders redevelopment in a community completely infeasible. Allowing this level of density by-right in our neighbourhoods is the bare minimum we can do to ensure our communities are not locked into a cycle of decline, or a cycle of gentrification. While it's not affordable for lower-class Calgarians, this lower price tag is easier to create non-market options with. Also, as explored by a paper published by the Calgary Drop-In Centre, easing housing competition for even upper-class Calgarians has rippling effects on affordability as cheaper housing becomes more available.</p>
<h2><strong>Rezoning for flexibility!</strong></h2>
<p>Low-scale incrementalism is appropriate everywhere, and it's only the beginning.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/Pasted-image-20240522125008.png" alt="" width="1079" height="962" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522125008-xs.png 300w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522125008-sm.png 480w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522125008-md.png 768w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522125008-lg.png 1024w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522125008-xl.png 1360w ,https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/media/posts/5/responsive/Pasted-image-20240522125008-2xl.png 1600w"></figure>
<p>One of our friends Alex Williams said "We can handle the growth, but we cannot handle the decline" — Calgary is changing. Not only are communities unable to adapt for their peoples' individual needs; many communities are no longer able to support schools, reliable public transit, local businesses, or infrastructure upgrading. The C in R-CG stands for contextual. Height limits on new development encourage maximum density in redeveloping communities, and smaller, incremental changes elsewhere. This is a long-term change designed to allow communities to adapt to their own needs over time. Creating opportunities for seniors to downsize and live near family, for student rentals near post-secondary, for multi-generational redevelopment. Humans are complex, we can't plan for our communities' needs, so we need to give them the tools to enact change on their own terms.</p>
<p><strong>Join the conversation! Make your voice heard!</strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>This is the first post of StrongTownsCalgary Blog</title>
        <author>
            <name>StrongTownsCalgary</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/this-is-the-first-post-of-strongtownscalgary-blog.html"/>
        <id>https://blog.strongtownscalgary.ca/this-is-the-first-post-of-strongtownscalgary-blog.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-17T13:49:38-06:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content></content>
    </entry>
</feed>
